[MUSIC]
[음악]
In this module, we've seen how regression can be used to predict house prices and
이 모듈에서 회귀분석이 주택 가격 예측을
also be useful in a wide range of other applications.
포함한 다양한 분야에서 사용될 수 있음을 보았습니다
So, in the introduction to this course, Carlos introduced this machine
이 강의 도입부에서 카를로스가 기계학습 파이프라인을 소개했는데
learning pipeline, where we go from data, which gets shoved
데이터를 기계학습 알고리즘에
into some machine learning method, and we use that to derive intelligence.
집어넣어서 지능을 끌어내는 방법이었습니다
Well, let's dig into this block diagram and expand it, now that we've seen
기계학습 도구를 공부했으니 이제
these some of these machine learning tools, in a little bit more detail.
블록 다이어그램을 펼쳐서 자세히 살펴봅시다
Okay, so now we know what we actually use to fit our data is some training data set,
훈련 데이터 세트에 맞추려면 뭘 써야 하는지 이제 압니다
so that's gonna be our data.
데이터지요
And in our housing application,
주택 예제에서
where we're going to predict the price of some house,
특정 주택 가격을 예측하는데
the data that we collected was, we had this table of the house ID,
수집한 데이터는 주택 ID, 주택 특성,
and some set of house attributes, as well as the house's sales price.
주택 판매 가격이 담겨있는 표였습니다
And we had this for a whole bunch of houses in our neighborhood, and
근처 주택에서 이런 정보를 수집해
we collected this data into some table.
표 형태로 변환합니다
So, that represented our training data set.
이게 훈련 데이터 세트가 됩니다
And then we took that data, and what we did was shoved it through some feature
데이터를 가지고 특징 추출기에 집어넣는데
extractor, which in this case is a very simple feature extractor,
이 경우에는 아주 간단한 추출기를 써서
where we just choose some subset of the house attributes.
주택 특성의 일부만을 선택합니다
So, in the examples we looked at, X, our set of features,
예제에서 특징 세트 x는
represented things, like, we looked at square feet of the house,
주택 평수,
and we also looked at number of bathrooms.
화장실 개수 등을 나타냅니다
And we talked about possibly using more features.
추가할만한 다른 특징에 대해서도 알아봤습니다
Again, we'll talk about that more in the regression course, but
회귀 강의에서 더 깊이 다루겠지만
those were two that we examined in this module.
이 모듈에서 검토한 둘은 이렇습니다
And so then, what did we do with these features?
그럼 이 특징들로 뭘 하나요?
Well, our goal was to take these features and
목표는 이 특징을 가지고
have some type of model that led to a prediction of the house price.
주택 가격 예측에 도움이 되는 모델을 세우는 것입니다
Okay, so our output, the intelligence that
결과물인 지능은
we're deriving, is the predicted house price.
예측 주택 가격입니다
And we're going to do this for every house in our training data set.
훈련 데이터 세트의 모든 주택에 이 과정을 반복합니다
We're gonna take its associated features, and
연관 특징을 가져다
shove it through this machine learning model, and predict the house price.
기계학습 모델에 집어넣어서 주택 가격을 예측합니다
And what's the machine learning model we talked about?
어떤 기계학습 모델을 알아봤죠?
Well, in this case, it's regression.
이 경우 회귀분석입니다
That's our specific machine learning model that we're looking at here.
우리가 살펴본 기계학습 모델입니다
Okay, but remember that this machine learning model had some set of parameters.
기계학습 모델에는 파라미터 세트가 있다는 사실을 상기해 봅시다
Okay, so the parameters we call W.
파라미터를 w라고 부르죠
These are the weights on our features.
각 특징에 대한 가중치입니다
So, for example, it's the weight on square feet or number of bathrooms, and so on.
평수나 화장실 개수 등에 대한 가중치지요
More technically, these are called regression coefficients.
전문용어로는 회귀계수라고 합니다
And we talked about estimating these parameters from data,
데이터를 통한 파라미터 예측을 알아봤고
so our W hat is our estimate of these parameters.
w 모자가 예측 파라미터임을 밝혔습니다
And how did we talk about doing that?
어떻게 한다고 했지요?
Well, we took our predicted output, so
예측 결과물을 가지고
our predicted house price, and we compared it to the true house price.
이 경우엔 예측 주택 가격인데, 진짜 주택 가격과 비교합니다
So, the actual sales price that we recorded in our training data table.
훈련 데이터 표에 기록된 실제 판매 가격이지요
So, Y, here, is our actual sales
여기 y가 훈련 데이터에 있는 주택의
price for the houses in our training data.
실제 판매 가격이 됩니다
And we compare to the predicted house price.
이걸 예측 주택 가격과 비교합니다
And we use a quality metric to measure how well we're doing with our prediction,
품질 척도 w 모자가 파라미터인 모델을 통한
using our model, using W hat as the parameters of that model.
예측이 얼마나 정확한지 측정합니다
Well, how well are we doing?
얼마나 정확한가요?
What was the error metric we talked about?
어떤 오류 척도를 알아봤죠?
The error metric we talked about was something called residual sum of squares,
오류 척도는 잔차제곱합이었죠
where we just sum up the square difference between the actual house sales price and
실제 주택 판매 가격과 예측 주택 판매 가격 간의 차이를 제곱한 값을 더합니다
the predicted house sales price, summing over all houses in our training data set.
훈련 데이터 세트에 있는 모든 주택에 대해 이를 행합니다
Okay, so our quality metric is gonna take our predictions and
품질 척도는 예측과 실제 주택 판매 가격 결과를 놓고
our actual house sales observations, spit out this error, and
오류를 계산한 다음
it's gonna go into a machine learning algorithm that's gonna be used to update
기계학습 알고리즘에 집어넣어 모델의
the weights, update our parameters of our model.
파라미터인 가중치를 갱신합니다
And we're gonna talk about this machine learning algorithm, or
기계학습 알고리즘과 그 변형을 알아보게 될텐데
different variants of it, a lot more in the actual course on regression.
회귀 강의에서 더 깊이 들어갈 예정입니다
But this is the overall flowchart for this machine learning method for
이게 주택 가격 예측 문제에 대한
our house prediction problem.
기계학습 방법론의 전체 플로 차트입니다
And this loop here, where we're taking our predictions,
여기 루프에서 예측을 놓고 실제 판매 가격에 대한
computing our error relative to the actual house sales prices,
오류를 계산하여 가중치,
and updating the weights or our model parameters.
모델 파라미터를 갱신하게 되는데
This process tends to happen in an iterative way,
이 과정은 순환되는 경향이 있어
where we update values again and again.
값을 계속해서 갱신하게 됩니다
Okay, so if we abstract a way, what we see is we have some training data set.
이렇게 추상화를 하면 훈련 데이터 세트,
We have some feature extraction process.
특징 추출 과정,
We have some machine learning model.
기계학습 모델이 남게 됩니다
And it's gonna produce some intelligence, which in this case is a prediction.
지능을 만들어 내게 되는데 이 경우는 예측입니다
And we're gonna assess the quality of our intelligence with some quality measure.
지능을 품질 기준으로 평가합니다
And we're gonna use that error or accuracy, depending which way we're
그렇게 구한 오류나 정확도를
thinking about measuring it, to adjust our model parameters using some algorithm.
특정 알고리즘을 거치게 한 다음 모델 파라미터를 조정합니다
And we're gonna see this type of flow for machine learning again and again.
기계학습에서 이런 형식의 흐름을 계속 보게 될 것입니다
In this module, we've seen how to take our data and
이 모듈에서는 데이터를 가지고
derive intelligence using something called regression,
특징과 결과를 연관짓는 모델을 만드는 회귀분석이란 도구를 이용해
where we have a model that relates our features to our output.
지능을 이끌어내는 법을 배웠습니다
And we talked about this in the context of predicting house values, and
주택 가치 예측에 연관해 알아봤고
you also work through a really interesting IPython notebook.
무척 재밌는 IPython 노트북을 통해 작업했습니다
And from this, you should be able to deploy really interesting regression
이를 통해 아주 흥미로운 회귀분석 모델을
models in practice now.
실무에서 세울 수 있을 것입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]